Guide to the John Gunther Papers 1935-1967
University of Chicago Library
- Series XII: Inside Russia Today
  - Subseries 10: Research Materials
    - Chapter 14, Puppet theater Music, musicians, classics, jazz Movies, television Socialist realism (Box 96, Folder 18)
    - Chapter 14-Art, artists, Picasso (Box 96, Folder 19)
    - Chapter 14-Miscellaneous, outlines (Box 96, Folder 20)
    - Chapter 16A, Women, children, divorce, prostitution, Puritanism Religion, Jews, churches Sports, jokes (Box 97, Folder 1)
    - Chapter 16A, Crime, law, civil liberties, dissent Ferment, discontent, freedom Miscellaneous, outlines (Box 97, Folder 2)
    - Chapter 16BArmy, Air force, aviation Navy, submarines Strategy, missiles, A-bombs, satellites, miscellaneous (Box 97, Folder 3)
    - Chapter 16B-What Have They Got? (Box 97, Folder 4)
    - Chapter 17-Agriculture, "virgin" lands, state farms, collectives, problems (Box 97, Folder 5)
    - Chapter 17-Industry, M. G. Peruvkhin, decentralization, reorganization (Box 97, Folder 6)
    - Chapter 17-Budget, loans, taxes, labor, consumer goods, roads, cars (Box 97, Folder 7)
    - Chapter 17-Socialism, industrialization, miscellaneous (Box 97, Folder 8)
    - Chapter 17A, Leningrad Leningrad-Hermitage, Natural History Museum, Pavlov Institute (Box 97, Folder 9)
    - Chapter 17A-Kiev (Box 97, Folder 10)
    - Chapter 17A, Ukraine Odessa Flight-Leningrad-Minsk-Kiev (Box 97, Folder 11)
    - Chapter 18-Crimea, Yalta (Box 97, Folder 12)
    - Chapter 18-Pobeda Cruise, Novorossiisk, Sochi, Sukhumi (Box 97, Folder 13)
    - Chapter 18-Georgia (Box 97, Folder 14)
    - Chapter 18, Tiflis Caucasus, outlines (Box 97, Folder 15)
    - Chapter 19-Samarkand (Box 97, Folder 16)
    - Chapter 19Bukhara, Tashkent Alma-Ata, Kazakhstan (Box 98, Folder 1)
    - Chapter 19-Turkmenistan, Tadzhikistan, Kirghizia, Central Asia (Box 98, Folder 2)
    - Chapter 19-Lost Peoples-Volga Germans, Kalmuks, Karachays, Balkars, Chechen-Ingush (Box 98, Folder 3)
    - Chapter 19-Miscellaneous, Outlines (Box 98, Folder 4)
    - Chapter 20-Foreign policy (Box 98, Folder 5)
    - Chapter 20-Satellites, Yugoslavia, China (Box 98, Folder 6)
    - Chapter 20-Far East, Middle East, Scandinavia, Western hemisphere (Box 98, Folder 7)
    - Chapter 21-22-Coexistence (Box 98, Folder 8)
    - Chapter 21-22-Generalizations (Box 98, Folder 9)
    - Chapter 22-Trends (Box 98, Folder 10)
    - Appendix-Personalities (Box 98, Folder 11)
    - Check sheets, watch sheets, questions (Box 98, Folder 12)
    - Permissions, acknowledgments, sources (Box 98, Folder 13)
    - Notes on corrections (Box 98, Folder 14)
    - Names (Box 98, Folder 15)
    - Jane Gunther's notes (corrections) (Box 98, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous articles, Confidential interview with Jawaharlal Nehru by Joseph Harsch "Kremlin vs. Stalin-An-Up-To-Now-Appraisal" by unknown commentator Copy of letter from J. Nehru to N. Bulganin, Nov. 7, 1956, relative to British-French-Israeli invasion of Egypt (Box 98, Folder 17)
    - Translation of article reviewing Inside Russia Today in Literaturnaya gazeta, September 18, 1958 (Box 98, Folder 18)
- Series XIII: Taken at the Flood-The Story of Albert D. Lasker
  TAKEN AT THE FLOOD, published in 1960, is Gunther's only full-length biography. It is the story of Albert D. Lasker, president of Lord and Thomas and called the "Father of Modern Advertising." The materials concerning this book are contained in nine boxes. The manuscripts are as follows:
  1. Original manuscript, typed and revised by the author
  2. First Revision or Second Draft, which is heavily revised. Those pages most heavily revised necessitated retyping and were added to the complete manuscript of this draft. The original manuscripts of these pages are filed separately.
  3. Printer's Copy, which is also heavily revised by the author. Those pages most heavily revised were retyped and added to the Printer's Copy. The original manuscripts of these pages are filed separately.
  4. Galley Proofs, with author's corrections and additions.
  The revisions on the various manuscripts are perhaps more extensive for this book than for any other of Gunther's works.
  The Informational Correspondence is quite extensive. There is little printed matter on Albert Lasker and Gunther corresponded with Lasker's family, his friends, and former business associates for information and clarification on certain aspects of his life. Included in this section are long memoranda from the Lasker family suggesting revisions of the First Draft, to most of which Gunther agreed. Among the letters of interest are those from former Senator William Benton, a one-time employee in Lasker's firm, Emerson Foote, vice-president of McCann-Brickson and a former vice-president of Lord and Thomas, Alexander de Seversky, the aeronautical engineer, and Lewis Strauss, Chairman of the Atomic Energy Commission. There are only two folders of Post-Publication correspondence, many of the letters to Gunther relating additional stories about Lasker or different versions of some story in the published work.
  The primary source material for the Lasker book is interview notes. All of the interviewees have been identified in the guide. Among them are William Benton, Fairfax Cone, Samuel Goldwyn, Paul Hopkins, Robert Hutchins, Anna Rosenberg, Alexander de Seversky, Herbert Bayard Swope, and David Sarnoff.
  There is also one box which might be classified "The Papers of Albert D. Lasker." This box includes correspondence to and from Lasker. copies of correspondence, a copy of Lasker's reminiscences recorded and transcribed by the Oral History Research Office of Columbia University, copies of Lasker's testimony before various congressional committees, and other materials. Of special interest is the correspondence between Lasker and Senator James Murray and his staff concerning congressional action on cancer research and aid to medical education and the correspondence concerning Lasker's resignation as a University of Chicago trustee in 1942.
  - Subseries 1: Original Manuscript
    - Chapter 1 A Glimpse of Things to Come (Box 99, Folder 1)
    - Chapter 2 Out of the Texas Frontier (Box 99, Folder 2)
    - Chapter 3 A Meteor Let Loose (Box 99, Folder 3)
    - Chapter 4 Early Years at Lord & Thomas (Box 99, Folder 4)
    - Chapter 5 Salesmanship in Print (Box 99, Folder 5)
    - Chapter 5A Chicago Days (6) (Box 99, Folder 6)
    - Chapter 6 First Taste of Politics (7) (Box 99, Folder 7)
    - Chapter 7 Baseball (8) (Box 99, Folder 8)
    - Chapter 8 Washington and the Shipping Board (9) (Box 99, Folder 9)
    - Chapter 9 Back to Advertising-The Great Accounts (10) (Box 99, Folder 10)
    - Chapter 10 More Chicago Days (11) (Box 99, Folder 11)
    - Chapter 11 Zenith (12-13) (Box 99, Folder 12)
    - Chapter 12 Deprivation, Discontent, Despair (14) (Box 99, Folder 13)
    - Chapter 13 Mary (15) (Box 99, Folder 14)
    - Chapter 13A The End of Lord & Thomas (17) (Box 99, Folder 15)
    - Chapter 14 Money (18) (Box 100, Folder 1)
    - Chapter 15 New York, Fun, and Friends (19) (Box 100, Folder 2)
    - Chapter 16 New Worlds in Art... (20) (Box 100, Folder 3)
    - Chapter 16A... and Medicine (21) (Box 100, Folder 4)
    - Chapter 17 Terminus (22) (Box 100, Folder 5)
    - Sources and Acknowledgments (Box 100, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 2: First Revision (Second Draft)
    - Retyped pages for 2nd Draft-Chapter 1 (Box 100, Folder 7)
    - Retyped pages for 2nd Draft-Chapters 2-8 (Box 100, Folder 8)
    - Retyped pages for 2nd Draft-Chapters 9-13 (Box 100, Folder 9)
    - Retyped pages for 2nd Draft-Chapters 14-22, Sources (Box 100, Folder 10)
    - Chapters 1-2 (Box 100, Folder 11)
    - Chapters 3-4 (Box 100, Folder 12)
    - Chapters 5-6 (Box 100, Folder 13)
    - Chapters 7-8 (Box 100, Folder 14)
    - Chapters 9-10 (Box 100, Folder 15)
    - Chapters 11-12 (Box 100, Folder 16)
    - Chapters 13-14 (Box 100, Folder 17)
    - Chapters 15-16 (Box 100, Folder 18)
    - Chapters 17-18 (Box 101, Folder 1)
    - Chapters 19-20 (Box 101, Folder 2)
    - Chapters 21-22 (Box 101, Folder 3)
    - Sources and Acknowledgments (Box 101, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 3: Printer's Copy
    - Retyped pages for printer's Copy-Chapters 1-19 (Box 101, Folder 5)
    - Retyped pages for printer's Copy-Chapters 20-21 (Box 101, Folder 6)
    - Excerpts of correspondence inserted in text (Box 101, Folder 7)
    - Chapter 1 (Box 101, Folder 8)
    - Chapters 2-3 (Box 101, Folder 9)
    - Chapter 4 (Box 101, Folder 10)
    - Chapter 5 (Box 101, Folder 11)
    - Chapter 6 (Box 101, Folder 12)
    - Chapter 7 (Box 101, Folder 13)
    - Chapters 8-9 (Box 101, Folder 14)
    - Chapter 10 (Box 101, Folder 15)
    - Chapter 11 (Box 101, Folder 16)
    - Chapters 12-13 (Box 101, Folder 17)
    - Chapters 14-15 (Box 102, Folder 1)
    - Chapters 16-17 (Box 102, Folder 2)
    - Chapters 18-19 (Box 102, Folder 3)
    - Chapters 20-21 (Box 102, Folder 4)
    - Chapter 22, Sources and Acknowledgments (Box 102, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 4: Galley Proofs
    - Chapters 1-4 (Box 102, Folder 6)
    - Chapters 5-8 (Box 102, Folder 7)
    - Chapters 9-12 (Box 102, Folder 8)
    - Chapters 13-16 (Box 102, Folder 9)
    - Chapters 17-20 (Box 102, Folder 10)
    - Chapters 21-22, Sources and Acknowledgments (Box 102, Folder 11)
    - Original manuscripts of galley inserts (Box 102, Folder 12)
  - Subseries 5: Miscellaneous Materials
    - Miscellaneous original manuscript pages and fragments of pages (Box 102, Folder 13)
    - Corrected pages of carbon copy (Cass Canfield) (Box 102, Folder 14)
    - Sketches on life of Albert Lasker (Box 102, Folder 15)
    - Detzer-Robichaud notes on Albert Lasker (Box 102, Folder 16)
    - Printed, near-print materials on Albert Lasker (Box 102, Folder 17)
  - Subseries 6: Informational Correspondence
    - William Benton (Box 103, Folder 1)
    - Mary and Leigh Block (Box 103, Folder 2)
    - Frances Lasker Brody (Box 103, Folder 3)
    - John T. Cahill and staff (Box 103, Folder 4)
    - Emerson Foote (Box 103, Folder 5)
    - Alfred Frankfurter (Box 103, Folder 6)
    - Robert Koretz (Box 103, Folder 7)
    - Edward Lusker (Box 103, Folder 8)
    - Mary Lasker and staff (Box 103, Folder 9)
    - Anna M. Rosenberg (Box 103, Folder 10)
    - Arthur Schlesinger, Jr. (Box 103, Folder 11)
    - Alexander de Seversky (Box 103, Folder 12)
    - Lewis L. Strauss (Box 103, Folder 13)
    - A-G (Box 103, Folder 14)
    - H-Z (Box 103, Folder 15)
    - Post-publication correspondence A-K (Box 103, Folder 16)
    - Post-publication correspondence L-Z (Box 103, Folder 17)
  - Subseries 7: Research Notes
    - Interview notes, William Benton (Former Senator, Publisher, Britannica) (Box 104, Folder 1)
    - Interview notes, Edward L. Bernays (Public Relations Counsel) Leigh Block (Inland Steel Co.) (Box 104, Folder 2)
    - Interview notes, Mrs. Leigh Block (Mary Lasker) (Box 104, Folder 3)
    - Interview notes, Dr. George Brazill (National Guard General, dentist) (Box 104, Folder 4)
    - Interview notes, Mrs. Sidney Brody (Frances Lasker) (Box 104, Folder 5)
    - Interview notes, Edward E. Brown (First National Bank, Chicago) (Box 104, Folder 6)
    - Interview notes, John T. Cahill (Attorney) (Box 104, Folder 7)
    - Interview notes, Fairfax Cone (Foote, Cone, and Belding) (Box 104, Folder 8)
    - Interview notes, Sheldon Coons (Former Vice-President, Lord and Thomas) (Box 104, Folder 9)
    - Interview notes, Dr. George Daniels (Psychiatrist) Morris Ernst (Attorney, author) (Box 104, Folder 10)
    - Interview notes, Emerson Foote (Foote, Cone, and Belding) (Box 104, Folder 11)
    - Interview notes, Don Francisco (Former President, Lord and Thomas) (Box 104, Folder 12)
    - Interview notes, Alfred Frankfurter (Editor. Art News) (Box 104, Folder 13)
    - Interview notes, Bernard Gimbel (Merchant) Samuel Goldwyn (Motion Picture Producer) Lou Hartman (L. H. Hartman Advertising Co.) (Box 104, Folder 14)
    - Interview notes, John D. Hertz (Financier) Paul Hoffman (Studebaker Corp., E.C.A., Ford Foundation) (Box 104, Folder 15)
    - Interview notes, Albert Hopkins (Attorney) Robert M. Hutchins (Former Chancellor, Univ. of Chicago) (Box 104, Folder 16)
    - Interview notes, Eleanor Kerrigan (Former secretary) Edwin Knopf (Motion Picture Producer) Robert Koretz (Vice-President, Foote, Cone, and Belding) (Box 104, Folder 17)
    - Interview notes, Edward Lasker (Son, attorney) (Box 104, Folder 18)
    - Interview notes, Edward Lasker (continued) (Box 104, Folder 19)
    - Interview notes, Loula Lasker (sister) (Box 104, Folder 20)
    - Interview notes, Mary Woodward Lasker (Mrs. Albert D. Lasker) (Box 105, Folder 1)
    - Interview notes, Mary Lasker (continued) (Box 105, Folder 2)
    - Interview notes, Mary Lasker (continued) (Box 105, Folder 3)
    - Interview notes, Dr. Richard Loeb (Columbia Presbyterian Hospital) Earle Ludgin (Earle Ludgin, Inc., Advertising) (Box 105, Folder 4)
    - Interview notes, Leonard Lyons (Columnist) (Box 105, Folder 5)
    - Interview notes, Ernst Mahler (Kimberly-Clark Corp.) (Box 105, Folder 6)
    - Interview notes, Samuel Marx (Architect) Merrill Meigs (Aviation expert) André Meyer (Banker) (Box 105, Folder 7)
    - Interview notes, Nancy Morris (Maid) (Box 105, Folder 8)
    - Interview notes, David Noyes (Former Vice-President, Lord and Thomas) (Box 105, Folder 9)
    - Interview notes, Emery Reves (Agent and art collector) (Box 105, Folder 10)
    - Interview notes, Anna M. Rosenberg (Assistant Secretary of Defense) (Box 105, Folder 11)
    - Interview notes, David Sarnoff (Radio Corporation of America) (Box 105, Folder 12)
    - Interview notes, Richard Simon (Simon & Schuster, Publishers) Alexander de Seversky (Aviation expert) (Box 105, Folder 13)
    - Interview notes, Ralph Sollitt (Former President, Lord and Thomas) (Box 105, Folder 14)
    - Interview notes, Benjamin Sonnenberg (Public Relations Counselor) David Stern (Broker) (Box 105, Folder 15)
    - Interview notes, Herbert Bayard Swope (Author and editor) John Wheeler (North American Newspaper Alliance) Norman Winston (Financier and Housing Specialist) (Box 105, Folder 16)
    - Interview notes, Miscellaneous (Box 105, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous notes on Albert Lasker (Box 106, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous notes on Albert Lasker (Box 106, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous notes on Lasker family (Box 106, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous notes on Lord and Thomas and advertising (Box 106, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous notes on politics (Box 106, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous notes on Manton case (Box 106, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous notes on sports (Box 106, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous notes on health (Box 106, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous notes on art (Box 106, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous notes (Box 106, Folder 10)
    - Notes on sources and acknowledgments, names (Box 106, Folder 11)
    - Outlines, agendas, possible titles (Box 106, Folder 12)
    - Check sheets, additions, watch sheets (Box 106, Folder 13)
    - Check sheets, additions, watch sheets (Box 106, Folder 14)
    - Check sheets, watch sheets, additions (Box 106, Folder 15)
  - Subseries 8: Albert Lasker Materials
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence-A-L (Box 107, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence-M-Z (Box 107, Folder 2)
    - Copies of letters from Lasker to his father; Morris Lasker to his son (1915) (Box 107, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence concerning Lasker's resignation as University of Chicago Trustee-1942 (Box 107, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence with Senator James Murray of Montana and his staff concerning Congressional action on cancer research aid to medical education, etc.-January-June 1949 (Box 107, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence with Senator James Murray and staff-August 1949- January 1950 (Box 107, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence on federal aid to cancer research, aid to medical education, etc. (Box 107, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence concerning Lasker's trip to Israel, 1950 (Box 107, Folder 8)
    - "The Reminiscences of Albert Davis Lasker"-Oral History Research Office (Box 107, Folder 9)
    - "The Lasker Story…As He Told It"-Advertising Age (Published version of informal talk Lasker gave to employees of Lord and Thomas in 1925), 1952-53 (Box 107, Folder 10)
    - Copy of testimony by Lasker before senate committee on Cancer, Research bill, July 3, 1946 (Box 107, Folder 11)
    - Copy of testimony by Lasker before Senate Committee on Coordinate, Health Functions of the Federal Government, July 11, 1947 (Box 107, Folder 13)
    - Remarks made by Lasker at dinner in honor of Alexander Seversky, July 12, 1943 (Box 107, Folder 14)
- Series XIV: Inside Europe Today
  INSIDE EUROPE TODAY, published in 1961 was originally conceived as an article for Reader's Digest. Gunther, however, turned out the longest article, some 42,000 words, that the Digest had ever received, and it was never published in its entirety. Gunther then added to the material and extended it into a full-length book, approximately three times longer than the Reader's Digest manuscript. The materials concerning this work are contained in eight boxes. The manuscripts are as follows:
  1. Original manuscript: Reader/s Digest, typed and corrected by author
  2. First Revision or Second Draft-Reader's Digest, which is heavily revised
  3. Original Manuscript of Additional chapters, which are, in this instance, records of dictation
  4. First Revision or Second Draft of additional chapters, which is a typescript of the dictated chapters heavily revised by author
  5. Printers copy, which is a carbon copy of the material above which has been merged, However, it is heavily revised, with numerous retyped pages and inserts. Gunther employed the "cut and paste" method,
  6. Galley proofs, with author's corrections. Several of the chapters have been heavily revised.
  No post-publication correspondence was included in the original deposits. The informational correspondence, which is not extensive, concerns mainly factual material. Included among the material are several memoranda by Look officials on, the Polaris missile, interview notes of Louis Duff with Charles Wilson. Secretary of Defense and Admiral Arleigh Burke. Chief of Naval Operations, and a letter from the editorial research Department of Reader's Digest on Harold Macmillan's relationship with the American Macmillan Company.
  The majority of the notes are interview notes. Among those interviewed by Gunther were Willy Brandt, Ludwig Erhardt, Georges Bonnet, Jean Monnat, Giovanni Gronchi, Hugh Gaitskell, Selwyn LIoyu, Harold Macmillan, and numerous other European politicians and statesmen, embassy officials, and American journalists and radio commentators.
  - Subseries 1: Original Manuscript-Readers's Digest Manuscripts-First Draft
    - Chapter 1 By Way of Introduction (1) (Box 108, Folder 1)
    - Chapter 2 Some Points of Detail-The New Europe (1) (Box 108, Folder 2)
    - Chapter 3 The Old Man on the Rhine (2) (Box 108, Folder 3)
    - Chapter 4 Pressures in the Federal Republic (3) (Box 108, Folder 4)
    - Chapter 5 Berlin-Outpost and Pivot (4) (Box 108, Folder 5)
    - Chapter 5A Eastern Sector, Eastern Zone (5) (Box 108, Folder 6)
    - Chapter 6 The Person of de Gaulle (6) (Box 108, Folder 7)
    - Chapter 7 Changes and Perplexities in France (7) (Box 108, Folder 8)
    - Chapter 8 The Army, Algeria, and Africa (8) (Box 108, Folder 9)
    - Chapter 9 What's Going On in Italy (11) (Box 108, Folder 10)
    - Chapter 10 England, the Most Important Country (14) (Box 108, Folder 11)
    - Chapter 11 Defense, NATO, and the Common Market (15, 18, 19) (Box 108, Folder 12)
    - Chapter 12 A Few Paragraphs in Conclusion (24) (Box 108, Folder 13)
  - Subseries 2: Original Manuscript-Readers's Digest Manuscripts-Second Draft
    - Chapter 1 By Way of Introduction (Chapters 1 & 2 above) (1) (Box 108, Folder 14)
    - Chapter 2 The Old Man on the Rhine (2) (Box 108, Folder 15)
    - Chapter 3 Pressures in the Federal Republic (3) (Box 108, Folder 16)
    - Chapter 4 Berlin-Outpost and Pivot (4) (Box 108, Folder 17)
    - Chapter 5 Eastern Sector, Eastern Zone (Chapter 5A above (5) (Box 108, Folder 18)
    - Chapter 6 The Person of de Gaulle (6) (Box 108, Folder 19)
    - Chapter 7 Changes and Perplexities in France (7) (Box 108, Folder 20)
    - Chapter 8 The Army, Algeria, and Africa (8) (Box 108, Folder 21)
    - Chapter 9 What's Going On in Italy (11) (Box 109, Folder 1)
    - Chapter 10 England, the Most Important Country (14) (Box 109, Folder 2)
    - Chapter 11 Defense, NATO, and Nuclear Disarmament (15,18) (Box 109, Folder 3)
    - Chapter 12 At Sixes and Sevens (part of Chapter 11 above) (19) (Box 109, Folder 4)
    - Chapter 13 A Few Paragraphs in Conclusion (24) (Box 109, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 3: Records of Dictation for Additional Chapters-Original Manuscript
    - Chapter 9 The Benelux Constellation (9), Chapter 10 The Iberian Peninsula (10) (Box 109, Folder 6)
    - Chapter 12 Along the Mediterranean (12), Chapter 13 Austria Felix (13) (Box 109, Folder 7)
    - Chapter 17 The Establishment and the Opposition (17), Chapter 19 Scandinavia (20) (Box 109, Folder 8)
    - Chapter 21 Khrushchev at the Summit (21), Chapter 21A More About Mr. K. (22) Chapter 23 Satellites and Soviet Policy (23) (Box 109, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous inserts (Box 109, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 4: Manuscripts for Additional Chapters-Second Draft
    - Chapter 9 The Benelux Constellation (9) (Box 109, Folder 11)
    - Chapter 10 The Iberian Peninsula (10) (Box 109, Folder 12)
    - Chapter 12 Along the Mediterranean (12) (Box 109, Folder 13)
    - Chapter 13 Austria Felix (13) (Box 109, Folder 14)
    - Chapter 16 Macmillan (16) (Box 109, Folder 15)
    - Chapter 17 The Establishment and the Opposition (17) (Box 109, Folder 16)
    - Chapter 18 A Word on NATO (Part of Chapter 11 above) (18) (Box 109, Folder 17)
    - Chapter 19 At Sixes and Sevens (Expanded Chapter 12 above) (19) (Box 110, Folder 1)
    - Chapter 19 Scandinavia-The Outer Bastions (20) (Box 110, Folder 2)
    - Chapter 21 Khrushchev at the Summit (21) (Box 110, Folder 3)
    - Chapter 22 More About Mr. K. (22) (Box 110, Folder 4)
    - Chapter 23 Satellites and Soviet Policy (23) (Box 110, Folder 5)
    - Chapter 23 A Few Paragraphs in Conclusion (24) (Box 110, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous pages and fragments retyped (Box 110, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous pages and fragments retyped (Box 110, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 5: Printer's Copy
    - Chapter 1 (Box 110, Folder 9)
    - Chapter 2 (Box 110, Folder 10)
    - Chapter 3 (Box 110, Folder 11)
    - Chapter 4 (Box 110, Folder 12)
    - Chapter 5 (Box 110, Folder 13)
    - Chapter 6 (Box 110, Folder 14)
    - Chapter 7 (Box 111, Folder 1)
    - Chapter 8 (Box 111, Folder 2)
    - Chapter 9 (Box 111, Folder 3)
    - Chapter 10 (Box 111, Folder 4)
    - Chapter 11 (Box 111, Folder 5)
    - Chapter 12 (Box 111, Folder 6)
    - Chapter 13 (Box 111, Folder 7)
    - Chapter 14 (Box 111, Folder 8)
    - Chapter 15 (Box 111, Folder 9)
    - Chapter 16 (Box 111, Folder 10)
    - Chapter 17 (Box 111, Folder 11)
    - Chapter 18 (Box 111, Folder 12)
    - Chapter 19 (Box 111, Folder 13)
    - Chapter 20 (Box 111, Folder 14)
    - Chapter 21 (Box 111, Folder 15)
    - Chapter 22 (Box 111, Folder 16)
    - Chapter 23 (Box 111, Folder 17)
  - Subseries 6: Galley Proofs
    - Chapters 1-3 (Box 112, Folder 1)
    - Chapters 4-6 (Box 112, Folder 2)
    - Chapters 7-9 (Box 112, Folder 3)
    - Chapters 10-12 (Box 112, Folder 4)
    - Chapters 13-15 (Box 112, Folder 5)
    - Chapters 16-18 (Box 112, Folder 6)
    - Chapters 19-21 (Box 112, Folder 7)
    - Chapters 22-24 (Box 112, Folder 8)
    - Chapters 22-23, heavily revised page proofs (Box 112, Folder 9)
    - Second half, Chapter 17, revised galley proof (Box 112, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 7: Miscellaneous Manuscripts